Guide to the Institute for Independent Education records, 1984-2005.
Institute for Independent Education records, 1984-2005
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Institute for Independent Education records, 1984-2005.
6693
Institute for Independent Education.
7.2 cubic ft.
Computer Media, Correspondence, Financial Records, Maps/Charts, Memorabilia, Manuscripts, Newspapers, Photographs, Publications, Reports, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection includes approximately 200 brochures from the more than 400 independent schools across the United States and in the U.S. Virgin Islands; records of the activities of the Institute, including training workshop, public conferences, newsletters, reports on student achievement and other topics, based on original research data from funded projects, and transcripts of interviews with administrators, teachers, and parents are part of the collection; over 430 photographs and prints of Institute activities; the corporate history of the Institute, including correspondence and the minutes of the Board of Directors; a set of 50 Institute publications, including materials on teaching mathematics, research reports on African American education, directories of schools, workbooks for schools on accreditation protocols, and proceedings of national conferences.A collection of secondary and tertiary materials that helped either to shape or reinforce the Institute's philosophy, mission, and programs, including copies of articles from out-of-print books, scholarly and popular journals, and newspapers that discuss the education of African Americans, as well as drafts of some unpublished manuscripts from African American educators.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1984, Dr. Joan Davis Ratteray founded the Institute for Independent Education in Washington DC to provide technical assistance to independent community-based schools, especially those owned and operated by African Americans and located primarily in urban areas.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection includes approximately 200 brochures from the more than 400 independent schools across the United States and in the U.S. Virgin Islands; records of the activities of the Institute, including training workshop, public conferences, newsletters, reports on student achievement and other topics, based on original research data from funded projects, and transcripts of interviews with administrators, teachers, and parents are part of the collection; over 430 photographs and prints of Institute activities; the corporate history of the Institute, including correspondence and the minutes of the Board of Directors; a set of 50 Institute publications, including materials on teaching mathematics, research reports on African American education, directories of schools, workbooks for schools on accreditation protocols, and proceedings of national conferences.A collection of secondary and tertiary materials that helped either to shape or reinforce the Institute's philosophy, mission, and programs, including copies of articles from out-of-print books, scholarly and popular journals, and newspapers that discuss the education of African Americans, as well as drafts of some unpublished manuscripts from African American educators.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Institute for Independent Education.; Ratteray, Dr. Joan Davis.; Institute for Independent Education, Inc.
Subjects:
African Americans--Education.; African American students--United States.; Private Schools--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Brochures from Independent Schools and Related School Associations and Organizations
  - Expanded guide to the archives of the Institute For Independent Education, Inc., 2005 (Box 9)
  - Academic Enrichment Center - Washington D.C., 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounters - Chicago, Illinois, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adhiambo - Jackson, Mississippi, 1984-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adhiambo School - Jackson, Mississippi, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - African-American Academy for Accelerated Learning - Minneapolis, Minnesota, June 28, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Afrikan Free School - Harlem, New York, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Afrikan People's Action School - Trenton, New Jersey, 1982-1987, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aisha School - Detroit, Michigan, 1990-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alice Rouse Donaldson Education Self Help Center - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, August-September 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Allen Christian School - Jamaica, New York, 1986-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anacostia Bible Church Christian School - Washington D.C. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Atlanta Preparatory School - East Point, Georgia, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Barbara Taylor School - New York, New York, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Berean Institute - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bethel Christian School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1966, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bethel Christian School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bethel Christian School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Boggs Academy - Keysville, Georgia, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bosum Dzemawodzi Day School - Jamaica, New York (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brisbane Academy - Charlotte, North Carolina, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brito Miami Private School - Miami, Florida (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bruce-Guadalupe Community School - Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Caribbean Childrenspace - St. Croix, Virgin Islands (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Carolina Central Christian Academy - Columbia, South Carolina, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cecil L. Murray Education Center - Los Angeles, California, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Chad School / Chad Science Academy - Newark, New Jersey, 1985-2003 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Chesapeake Ability School - Alexandria, Virginia, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Children's Space - Long Beach, California, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Children's Store Front - New York, New York (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Chinese-American International School - San Francisco, California, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Chinese Bilingual School - San Francisco, California, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Chinquipin School - Highlands, Texas, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Christ Crusader Academy - New York, New York, 1986-1987, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Community Preparatory School - San Diego, California, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Concord Baptist School - Brooklyn, New York, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Corporate / Community School - Chicago, Illinois, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Cromwell Academy - Washington D.C., 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Cush Campus Schools - Brooklyn, New York, 1991-2003 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - De La Salle Academy - New York, New York, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dukette Catholic School - Flint, Michigan, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Ebon International Preparatory Academy - Forsyth, Georgia, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Escuela de la Raza Unida - Blythe, California, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Escuela Tlatelolco - Denver, Colorado, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Excelsior School - Atlanta, Georgia, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Faith Christian Academy - Detroit, Michigan (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Faulkner School - Chicago, Illinois, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Fellowship Academy - San Francisco, California, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Fellowship Bible Institute - San Francisco, California, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Fellowship Christian Academy - Dallas, Texas (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - First Christian Academy - Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Florence Jackson Academy - Atlanta, Georgia, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - For Love of Children Learning Center - Washington D.C. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Frederick Douglass Institute - St. Louis, Missouri, 1980-1998 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Frederick K. C. Price III Schools - Los Angeles, California, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Fuller Normal & Industrial Institute - Greenville, South Carolina, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - George Washington Carver Outdoor School, The - Washington D.C., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Gilbert Academy - New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Granville Academy - Trenton, New Jersey, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Greenforest Christian Academy - Decatur, Georgia, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hales Franciscan School - Chicago, Illinois, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Harambee Community School - Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Harambee Institute - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Harvard School, The - Chicago, Illinois, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Haugabrooks Academy, The New - Atlanta, Georgia (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Heart of the Earth Survival School - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hillside International Truth Center - Atlanta, Georgia, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Holy Angels Catholic School - Chicago, Illinois, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Holy Comforter (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Holy Redeemer Christian Academy - Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Holy Temple Christian Academy - Washington D.C., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hope Academy - Oakland, California, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hope Preparatory Academy - Chicago, Illinois, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hopi Mission School - Kykotsmovi, Arizona, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Houston Preparatory School, The - Houston, Texas, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Howalton School, The - Chicago, Illinois, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Humbolt Community Christian - Chicago, Illinois, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ideal School of Washington, The - Washington D.C., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Imani School - Houston, Texas, 1990-1999 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Independent School, The - Cleveland, Ohio, 1977-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - International Preparatory Institute - Atlanta, Georgia, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ivy Leaf School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1985-2003 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ivy Leaf School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1994-2005 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Jayne Wallace School - New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jericho City of Praise Christian - Washington D.C., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Jewels of Ann Private School - Washington D.C. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Johnson Preparatory Academy - Brooklyn, New York, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Joy of Jesus Academy - Detroit, Michigan (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Juanita Virgil Academy - Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Jubilee School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Larchwood Seventh Day Adventist - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Laurinburg Institute - Laurinburg, North Carolina, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Learning Tree Cultural Center, The - New York (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lincoln-Marti Schools - Miami, Florida, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lobias Murray Christian Academy - Dallas, Texas, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lotus Academy, The - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1992, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Malcolm X Shabazz Academy - Compton, California, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Manor School, The - St. Croix, Virgin Islands, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Marcus Garvey School - Los Angeles, California, 1983-1999 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Marcus Garvey School - Los Angeles, California, 1980-1999 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Marcus Garvey Academy of Arts & Sciences - Washington D.C., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Marotta Montessori School - Cleveland, Ohio, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mars Hill Elementary School - Chicago, Illinois, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - McGraw Learning Institute - Little Rock, Arkansas, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Mel Blount Youth Home, The - Claysville, Pennsylvania (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Melrose Community School - Bronx, New York, 1983-1993 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Miami Union Academy - Miami, Florida, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Michigan Institute for Child Development - Detroit, Michigan (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Mississippi Boulevard Christian Academy - Memphis, Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Modern School, The - New York, New York, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Monroe R. Saunders School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Mt. Airy Church of God in Christ - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Muhammed's Developmental School - Chicago, Illinois, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Nairobi Day School - East Palo Alto, California, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Nannie Helen Burroughs School - Washington D.C., 1923-1944, 1976-2003 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Nataki Talibah Schoolhouse of Detroit - Detroit, Michigan, 1982-1992 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Nation House Watoto School - Washington D.C., 1981-1993 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Nay-Ah-Shing School - Onamia, Minnesota, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - New Concept Development Center - Chicago, Illinois (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - New Covenant - Bronx, New York (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - New Life Christian Academy - Cincinnati, Ohio, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - New Psalmist Christian School, The - Baltimore, Maryland, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Nine Valley Shule - Buffalo, New York, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Nyrere Education Institute - New Brunswick, New Jersey, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Oasis, The Educational Center - Fort Worth, Texas, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Omowale Ujamaa School - Pasadena, California, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Paige Academy - Roxbury, Massachusettes, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Palmer Memorial Institute - Sedalia, North Carolina (Charlotte Hawkins Brown Memorial), 1915-1952, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pan-African University, The - Washington D.C., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Park Heights Street Academy - Baltimore, Maryland, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Paterson Come-Unity Schools - Paterson, New Jersey, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Penn Center Academy - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pine Forge Academy - Pine Forge, Pennsylvania, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Piney Woods Country Life School - Piney Woods, Mississippi, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Piney Woods Country Life School - Piney Woods, Mississippi, 1985-2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Piney Woods Country Life School - Piney Woods, Mississippi, 1975-1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pleasant Green Community School & Educational Center - Kansas City, Kansas, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Progressive Christian Academy - Macon, Georgia, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Providence St. Mel School - Chicago, Illinois, 1992-2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Providence St. Mel School - Chicago, Illinois, 1983-2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pyramid Elementary School - Detroit, Michigan, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ramah Jr. Academy - Cleveland, Ohio, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Randall Hyland School - Washington D.C., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Redemption Christian Academy - Troy, New York (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Renaissance Christian Academy - Suitland, Maryland, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Romar Academy - Atlanta, Georgia, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Roots Activity Learning Center - Washington D.C., 1986-1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sage Garden, The - Bronx, New York, 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Saints Academy - Lexington, Mississippi, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Sanctuary Christian Academy - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Sankofa Shule - Lansing, Michigan (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - School of the Good Shepherd, The - St. Croix, Virgin Islands, 1986-1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - School on the Hill, The - New York, New York, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Second New Hope Christian - Cleveland, Ohio (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Sheenway School and Culture Center - Los Angeles, California, 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Shelton's Primary Education Center - Berkeley, California, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Shule Mandela Academy - East Palo Alto, California (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Shule Nyansa Sua - East Palo Alto, California, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Shule Ya Taifa - East Palo Alto, California, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Sister Clara Mohammed School - Atlanta, Georgia, 1993-2002 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Sister Clara Mohammed School - San Diego, California (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Sister Clara Mohammed School - Washington D.C., 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Sister Clara Mohammed School - Boston, Massachusettes, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Sister Clara Mohammed School - New York, New York, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Sister Clara Mohammed School - Memphis, Tennessee (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Southern Normal School - Brewton, Alabama, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Southwest Atlanta Christian Academy - Atlanta, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Springtree/Snow Hill Institute for the Performing Arts - Snow Hill, Alabama, 1984-1993 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - St. Augustine Catholic School - Washington D.C. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - St. Augustine High School - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1965, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - St. Barnabas Episcopal School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - St. Dunstan's Episcopal School - St. Croix, Virgin Islands, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - St. Edmund's Academy - Chicago, Illinois, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - St. Frances-Charles Hall High School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - St. James School - Houston, Texas, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - St. Mary's Academy - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1988-1990, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - St. Philip's Academy, Newark, New Jersey, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - St. Philip's School and Community Center - Dallas Texas, 1986-2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - St. Stephen Lutheran Parochial School - Brooklyn, New York, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - St. Thomas Community School - New York, New York, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Storman-Stufflin School - St. Louis, Missouri, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tabernacle Christian Academy - Chicago, Illinois, 1983-1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Temple Academy - Nashville, Tennessee, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Timbuktu Academy - Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Tutorial Programs - Washington D.C., 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ujamaa Shule - Washington D.C., 1987-1990, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Union Baptist Excel Institute - Denver, Colorado, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Unselds' School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Urban Day School - Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - V. V. Reid Elementary School - Columbia, South Carolina, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Varnett Schools - Houston, Texas (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Virgie-Lu Children's Center (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Wade School - Washington D.C., 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Watch-Care Academy Denver, Colorado (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Watts Christian School - Los Angeles, California (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - West Angeles Christian Academy - Los Angeles, California (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - West Englewood Christian Academy - Chicago, Illinois (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - West Englewood Christian Community School - Chicago, Illinois (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Westside Academy - Los Angeles, California (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Westside Preparatory School - Chicago, Illinois (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Witness for Christ School - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Wonderland School - Houston, Texas, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Woodson, Academy, The - Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Word of Faith School - Detroit, Michigan (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Wynnefield Academy, Inc. - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Xavier Preparatory School - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - YMCA Academy, The - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Zion Demonstration Primary School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Zion Preparatory Academy - Seattle, Washington (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - African-American Association of Independent Schools, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Association of African-American Boarding Schools, 1994-2003 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Association of Historically Black Independent Schools of New York - New Jersey, 1993-2001 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Black Christian School Administrator's Network (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Council of Independent Black Institutions, The, 1984-2003 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Council of Independent Black Institutions, The, 1983-1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Delaware Valley Chapter of the National Technical Association, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - National African-American Educational Commission (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - New York Family Schools (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Toussaint Institute, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - United African Adolescent Rites of Passage Confederation, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Leads to New Schools, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Directories of Schools, 1988-1998 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Series II. Activities of the Institute for Independent Education 1984-2004
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1998-2004 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Activities of the Institute for Independent Education, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Reports on Significant Projects: An Overview, 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Projects: Math Alive!, July 27-August 9 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Projects: Parental Choice at Independent Neighborhood Schools for Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Projects: Chicago Independent Neighborhood Schools: A Pilot Study on Student Performance, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Projects: How To Develop and Maintain an Independent School, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Projects: How To Develop and Maintain an Independent School, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)